<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>infrastructure on baris.io</title><link>https://baris.io/tags/infrastructure/</link><description>Recent content in infrastructure on baris.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:36 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baris.io/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anatomy of a Dockerfile</title><link>https://baris.io/posts/anatomy-of-a-dockerfile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://baris.io/posts/anatomy-of-a-dockerfile/</guid><description>What is a Dockerfile? Dockerfile is a text document containing commands which can be run in sequence to assemble a docker image.
A sample Dockerfile from the official docs looks like this
# syntax=docker/dockerfile:1FROMnode:12-alpineRUN apk add --no-cache python g++ makeWORKDIR/appCOPY . .RUN yarn install --productionCMD [&amp;#34;node&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;src/index.js&amp;#34;]Why do we need them? There are millions of images on dockerhub that we can directly start using with a command like this.
docker run -it --rm -d -p 8080:80 --name web nginx For various reasons, we may want to customize these base images.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure as Code</title><link>https://baris.io/posts/infrastructure-as-code/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:02:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://baris.io/posts/infrastructure-as-code/</guid><description>Infrastructure as Code is the practice of managing and provisioning resources through version controlled definition files.
Things to note beforehand
Cloud providers like AWS, Azure and GCP allow us to provision new resources in mere minutes or even seconds. Multiple deployments to production every day is not an exceptional thing anymore We want to use a similar infrastructure for multiple environments(dev,staging,prod etc.) and regions Infrastructure on cloud does not only mean hosting applications on a virtual machine It also includes services we can use like data stores, queues/topics, network components, access rights/permission models and much more Utilizing these resources efficiently will help us move forward much faster What problem does it solve?</description></item><item><title>Observability 101</title><link>https://baris.io/posts/observability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 23:50:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://baris.io/posts/observability/</guid><description>Systems we build and maintain are becoming more complex and abstract with the increase in popularity of distributed systems, microservices, and cloud providers. With these new concepts, our view of failures has changed as well.
We have to assume things can and will break any time. So we have to make sure it is possible to understand what is happening within our services at any given time
Observability The Wikipedia definition of observability is</description></item></channel></rss>